人人影视 YYeTs.com
原创翻译 双语字幕
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
翻译｜慕风夕　cazorp　haloukeiti　ivy.sonya2012　丁丁猫哒　伊森先生
校对｜oktobertanz　　后期｜Sung1219
字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者
逃离地球
纳兰克星球 拯救可爱婴儿行动
斯考奇 斯考奇 你在吗
Scorch, Scorch, are you there?
快点 斯考奇 快回答
Come on, Scorch, get back to me.
你不会又做了什么不经大脑的事吧
You haven't run off and done something reckless, have you?
盖瑞 我们有麻烦了
Gary, we've got a problem!
这是我弟弟斯考奇
That's my brother, Scorch.
和往常一样 他又闯祸了
As usual, he's in trouble.
他是如何陷入这种境地的
How did he get into this mess?
那可是很久很久之前的事了
For that, I have to go back a long, long time.
四十七分钟前 拯救婴儿行动 纳兰克星球
Forty-seven minutes ago. Baby rescue mission. Planet Gnarlach.
轻点 斯考奇
Quiet, Scorch.
无论如何 不要惊醒纳兰克人
Whatever you do, don't wake the Gnarlachs.
这就是我 盖瑞・超新星
That's me, Gary Supernova.
我在指挥中心工作 就是说我掌控全局
I work in Mission Control, which means I control the mission.
可斯考奇却不这么认为
Scorch doesn't see it that way.
放松 盖瑞 他们睡得很死
Relax, Gary, they're fast asleep.
这就是纳兰克人
And that is a Gnarlach.
模样可怕 黏糊糊的
Scary, slimy,
而且 臭得惊天动地
and surprisingly stinky.
上传到蓝管上[仿油管]
Uploading that to Blue Tube.
盖瑞 这地方闻着
Gary, this place smells
比航天局的茅坑还臭
worse than the latrines at the BASA Academy.
[杯上文字：我爱和平]
多谢你[在我喝水的时候]告诉我
Thank you for that.
[仪表文字：詹姆斯・必应先生]
航天局是我诞生的地方
I was programmed at the BASA Academy.
那里只有进步的味道
The only thing I smelled there was progress.
闭嘴 詹姆斯
Zip it, James.
[模仿007系列 詹姆斯・邦德]
我叫必应 詹姆斯・必应
The name's Bing, by the way. James Bing.
好了 斯考奇 找到婴儿然后撤离
All right, Scorch, let's find those babies and get you out of there.
找到了 锁定目标飞船
Bingo. Spacecraft identified.
很好 现在谨慎地前行
Good. Now proceed with extreme caution.
拒绝 我要有范儿地前行
Negative. Proceeding with style.
别耍范儿了 斯考奇
Not style again! Scorch!
三星系统进入反转星系
Triple Star System into a Reverse Galaxy,
紧跟双重黑洞翻转
followed by a Double Black Hole with a twist!
平稳着陆
And he sticks the landing!
现在该谨慎前行了
Now proceed with caution.
斯考奇 婴儿应该就在前方
OK, Scorch, the babies should be straight ahead.
收到
Copy that.
不
No!
坏消息 老弟 晚了一步
Bad news, little brother. We're too late.
他们吃掉了婴儿
They've eaten the babies!
这太不公平了
It's so unfair!
斯考奇 婴儿就在你身后
Scorch, they're right behind you.
什么
What?
小家伙们
Hi, little guys.
斯考奇叔叔来救你们了
Uncle Scorch is here to rescue you.
盖瑞 要不要告诉斯考奇
Yeah, Gary, maybe tell Scorch
在这种情况下不要大声喧哗？
to keep his voice down in this situation?
- 仅供参考  - 斯考奇 安静点
- Just a thought.  - Scorch, quiet!
盖瑞 你真该来看看
Gary, you should see them.
他们太可爱了 真神奇
They're so cute. It's magical.
你会把周围这一群都吵醒的
You're gonna wake up the whole neighborhood.
这一群可不是什么好鸟
And this is not a good neighborhood.
- 躲猫猫  - 斯考奇
- Peekaboo!  - Scorch?
哎呦喂
Excuse me.
- 这下可好 又来了  - 斯考奇
- Good, here we go again.  - Scorch!
盖瑞 我们有麻烦了
Gary, we've got a problem!
麻烦还不小 你从来不听我指挥
Of course we have a problem. You never listen to me.
你说只有十二个纳兰克人 盖瑞
You said there were 12 Gnarlachs, Gary.
不 我说有一千两百个
No, I said 1200.
不 你没说过
Nope, I don't think you did.
- 有一千两百个纳兰克人  - 了解
- There are 1200 Gnarlachs down there.  - Got it.
- 一千两百个会吃婴儿的纳兰克人  - 了解
- Twelve-hundred baby-eating Gnarlachs.  - Got it.
一千两百个死敌 纳兰克人
Twelve-hundred of our archenemies, the Gnarlachs.
- 一千两百个  - 了解
- Twelve-hundred of 'em.  - Got it.
如果你说是一千两百个 我肯定会记得
Nope. I think I'd remember if you said 1200.
- 来真格的吧  - 好
- Now do your thing.  - OK.
前方二十码处是死亡山谷
Chasm of death in 20 yards and closing.
启用爪钩倒计时 三
Deploy grappling hook in three...
二
two...
一
one.
看到没
You see that?
这就是哥的能耐
That's what I'm talking about!
放马过来吧 丑八怪
Scorch me, baby!
小宝贝们 你们的座驾在此
Helpless babies, your chariot awaits.
就在你们眼皮底下呢
In your face, Gnarlachs!
婴儿我带走了
I got the babies!
不 不
No, no.
别哭 别哭 不怕 不怕 没事
Guys, no, no. It's OK. It's OK. It's OK.
别哭 别哭 不怕
No, no, no, don't cry. Don't cry.
- 盖瑞  - 正在处理
- Gary?  - I'm on it.
瞧着吧
Take that!
巴卜星球
超新星九号 获准在爸爸星球降落
Supernova-9, you are clear for landing on planet Dad!
先生 这里是禁飞区
This is a no-fly zone, mister.
真有意思 老爸
Very funny, Dad.
我认真的 控制台价值不菲 基普
I'm serious. This console's expensive, Kipper.
控制台？我就在这里 难以置信
Console? I mean... I mean, I'm right here. Unbelievable
能把飞船还给我吗
Can I have my spaceship back?
- 不行  - 爸爸 你什么都不让我做
- No.  - Dad, you never let me do anything.
好的 小心点
OK, but be careful.
知道 知道
Yeah, yeah, I know.
烫死了 烫死了
It burns! It burns!
抱歉 爸爸
Sorry,Dad.
好了 我们来玩乖乖坐的游戏吧
OK, let's play the game where you sit on your hands.
- 那游戏烂死了  - 盖瑞
- That game stinks.  - Gary!
做件好事 把这家伙停好
Be a pal, park this puppy, will ya?
启动远程协助
Activating remote assistance.
看老爸给你露一手
Time to watch your old man
让超新星九号完美着陆
bring in the Supernova-9 for a landing.
斯考奇回来了
Scorch is back!
我爱你 巴卜星球
I love you, planet Baab!
好棒
Cool!
老爸厉害吧
And that is how you do that.
- 盖瑞  - 什么 这也太吓人了
- Gary!  - What? OK, that's terrifying.
为什么你每次都要开启大头模式
Why do you always call me in jumbo-head mode?
我们收到星系中未知区域的求救信号
We've received an SOS from an uncharted sector of the galaxy.
准备让斯考奇执行下一个任务
Prepare for Scorch's next mission.
收到 长官 前往何处
Copy that, boss. Where are we headed?
去黑暗星球
He's going to the Dark Planet.
莉娜 你疯了吗
Lena, are you crazy?
我…重新措辞一下
Let me... rephrase that.
黑暗星球得名的原因是去的人无一生还
They call it the Dark Planet because nobody ever comes back.
这无异于去黑洞送死
It's like going into a black hole.
他一小时后出发
He leaves in an hour.
他要去黑暗星球？酷毙了
He's going to the Dark Planet? Wicked!
呆在这里 不许乱碰
Stay here. Don't touch anything.
没人会去黑暗星球
And nobody's going to the Dark Planet.
我们要去黑暗星球了
We are going to the Dark Planet!
- 斯考奇  - 斯考奇 我有个问题
- Scorch!  - Scorch, one question!
别提问 只拍照
No questions, just pictures.
好极了
Yeah, baby!
抱歉 斯考奇 斯考奇・超新星
Excuse me, Scorch! Scorch Supernova!
前排这位美丽的女士请提问
Yes, the beautiful young lady in the front row.
甜心 欢迎回家
Sweetie. Welcome home.
- 嘉比 这是现场直播  - 对了
- Gabby, we're live.  - Right.
跟我们说说行动的事吧
Tell us about the mission.
黑暗星球
The Dark Planet.
即便对我来说 也是凶险异常
It's heroic, even for me.
从没有人活着回来
No one has ever come back alive.
抱歉 不好意思 借过
Pardon me. Excuse me. Coming through.
- 你有时间准备吗  - 不 不用准备
- Have you had time to prepare?  - No, no, we haven't.
这是盖瑞・超新星 我的老弟
Gary Supernova, my baby brother.
事实上 我比他大
Fact check. I'm older than him.
盖瑞在书呆子工厂鼓捣出许多小破发明
Gary works all the gizmos and bleep-bloops here in the nerd factory.
我在指挥中心工作
I work in Mission Control.
我们用交互动力场矩阵来实现…
We use a trans-inducified field matrix to...
今天的《无聊报道》到此结束
And that's today's edition of The Boring Report.
请继续 嘉比
Back to you, Gabby.
我是巴卜星电视台的嘉比・泡泡娃
For BNN, this is Gabby Babblebrock,
在航天局总部为您现场播报
reporting live from BASA headquarters.
- 我要娶她  - 我为她感到遗憾
- I'm gonna marry that girl.  - And I feel sorry for her.
听着 我们对黑暗星球几乎一无所知
Now, listen, we know almost nothing about the Dark Planet.
没人知道 我们得推迟行动
No one does. We need to postpone the mission.
我也想 但我已经跟赞助商说好了
I would, but I've already contacted all my sponsors.
黑暗星球可乐 颠覆味觉体验
Dark Planet Cola! Destroy your taste buds!
含糖量百分之八百
This is 800 percent sugar.
所以对孩子更有益
That's what makes it good for kids.
而且 我已经拍了麦片包装的新形象
Plus, I've already taken the photos for the new cereal box.
什么时候
When?
尽享斯考奇麦片
J' Scorchios J'
- 刚刚  - “斯考奇麦片”？
- Just now.  - Scorchios?
每盒都有惊喜
There's a surprise in every box.
- 我玩得还不错  - 好了
- I'm pretty good at this.  - OK.
- 停下 停下  - 我能玩一整天
- Come... Come on!  - I could do this all day.
给我住手
Knock it off!
- 我们得认真考虑  - 考虑好了
- We need to think this through.  - I have.
有人向我求救 我得去帮助他们
Someone out there needs my help, and I am going to help them.
好 如果你现在去 我可帮不了你
OK, but if you go now, I can't help you help them.
盖瑞 你说得太对了
You know, Gary, you're absolutely right.
没必要急在一时
There's no sense in rushing things.
不然你去指挥室研究一下星系图
Why don't you pull up the star charts in the briefing room,
然后我们再和整个团队讨论
and we'll talk about this with the whole team.
没问题 伙计
You got it, partner.
这就够他忙的了 准备启动飞船
That should keep him busy. Let's fire up the ship!
电脑 载入黑暗星球的所有信息
Computer, load all information on the Dark Planet.
好的 稍等 文件扫描中 找到了
All right, just a sec. Scanning files, scanning files...Here we are.
黑暗星球 遥远的M级行星
The Dark planet. A remote M-class planet located 400 light-years
距金牛座分子云四百光年
past the Taurus Molecular Cloud.
光怪陆离 令人生畏
A strange and terrifying environment,
唯一已知的逆向进化发生地
the only known world in which evolution is taking place in reverse.
起初曾有过美丽智慧的生灵
It began with intelligent, attractive beings,
但很快被一群丑陋野蛮
but was soon overrun by ugly, aggressive
且傻的可怕的生物所取代
and quite terrifying dim-witted creatures.
好恶心
Yuck. Gross.
如你所见
As you can see,
从温文尔雅进化到野蛮呆傻
from gentle intelligence to savage stupidity.
他们有个奇怪的习俗
They have a strange custom of dividing themselves
即将领土划分为所谓的国家
into what they call countries,
一直就边境线问题争论不休
whose boundaries they often dispute
时常引发战争
which causes them to go to war.
基本模式似乎是
The pattern seems to be that
战胜国战后开始衰落
the winner of the war then goes into decline
而战败国富强
while the loser prospers.
我们还推断出 此星球的人们
We have also deduced that the people of this planet
依据面部毛发的丰密及诡异程度
choose leaders according to the oddity and profusion
来选择他们的领导人
of their facial hair.
他们崇尚金钱 汤羹
They worship money, soup,
马克笔 还有一种叫做牙线的东西
marker pens, something called dental floss
- 这个人叫科威尔  - 好可怕
- and this man, whose name is Cowell.  - Terrifying!
他因奇怪的口音出名 超级有钱
He's known for his strange accent, being very, very rich,
喜欢卖弄 在室内戴眼镜 我喜欢他
showing off, wearing glasses indoors. I like him.
一百零六名高级生物体
One hundred and six advanced life-forms
曾登陆黑暗星球
have landed on the Dark Planet
- 什么  - 试图建立友好的第一次接触
- What?  - to attempt friendly first contact.
结果全部下落不明
Not a single one has returned.
斯考奇叔叔
Uncle Scorch!
基普
Kipper!
你刚才帅呆了
You were awesome out there.
谢谢 伙计 你爸知道你在这里吗
Thanks, pal. Does your dad know you're here?
我应该在办公室等他的
I'm supposed to be waiting in his office,
但指挥中心太无聊了
but Mission Control is boring.
我能理解 是吧 全都是…
I know. Isn't it? It's all...
我更愿意当宇航员 像你一样
I'm more of an astronaut, like you.
这次也带我去吧
Take me with you this time.
你老爸会气死的
That sure would upset your dad,
虽然我挺想气气他的
which is something I love to do.
但听我说 基普
But I'll tell you what, Kipper...
如果我有麻烦 你要来救我
If I get into trouble, you come rescue me.
遵命 基普中尉 小小探险者 听凭差遣
Yes, sir! Lieutenant Kip, Junior Adventurer, at your service!
小小探险者 是吗
Junior Adventurer, are you?
- 这是什么  - 爆炸胶带
- What have we here?  - Blast tape!
准备好实战演习了吗
Ready for a training mission?
好 我们紧急迫降了
OK, we've crash-landed.
被一群黏糊糊绿油油的外星人包围
We're surrounded by a tribe of slimy, green aliens,
他们在不断缩小包围圈
and they are closing in on us.
你该怎么做 要这样 看好
What do you do? You do this! Watch!
- 吃我一炮  - 帅气
- Take that!  - Cool!
- 是时候收拾垃圾了  - 好棒
- Time to take out the trash!  - Awesome!
放马过来吧
Scorch me, baby!
我被击中了
They got me!
- 基普 全靠你了  - 棒极了
- Kipper, it's up to you.  - Wicked!
你们在干什么
What are you doing?
航天员训练
Astronaut training.
爆炸胶带？基普不能玩这个
Blast tape? Kip shouldn't be playing with it.
这东西都不应该让他看见
He shouldn't even be looking at it.
抱歉 巴瑞
Sorry, Barry.
回我办公室去
Back to my office.
再见 斯考奇叔叔
See ya, Uncle Scorch.
斯考奇
Scorch.
指挥中心
Mission Control,
我们这里出现了疯老爹危机
we've got a mad-dad situation here.
一点没错 我气疯了
You're darn right I'm mad...
飞船怎么启动了
Why is this ship on?
你打发我去楼上
You sent me upstairs
就是想偷偷去黑暗星球吧
so you could rush off to the Dark Planet.
没错
Yep.
我们不是说好了要延期吗
I thought we'd agreed to postpone the launch.
距发射还有三十分钟
Launch in T-minus 30 minutes.
斯考奇去那里太冒险了 拜托
It's too risky to send Scorch out there. Please.
省省吧 盖瑞 我警告你
Drop it, Gary. I'm warning you.
我是指挥官 没人听我的意见吗
I'm the mission controller. Does nobody here care what I think?
- 没  - 没人
- No.  - Not really.
- 没有  - 那我在这里还有什么意义
- Nope.  - Then why am I even here?
没事的 盖瑞 他早就驾轻就熟了
It'll be fine, Gary. He's done this a hundred times.
是我们已经驾轻就熟了 我们是搭档
We've done this a hundred times. We're a team.
我是大脑你是肌肉 你不是总这么说吗
I'm the brains and you're the brawn. That's what you always said.
我那么说是为了安慰你 老弟
I said it to make you feel better, little brother.
斯考奇 别再那么叫我了
Scorch, stop calling me that.
你一直在试图控制我的人生
You've been trying to control me your whole life.
这不就是你加入指挥中心的原因吗
Isn't that why you joined Mission Control?
我是在照顾你 兄弟之间就该这样
I'm looking out for you. That's what brothers do.
拜托 你坐在这里点按钮玩
Oh, please. You sit around here pushing buttons
我却在外面出生入死
while I am out there risking my neck.
是吗 我倒要看看没有我你要怎么办
Oh, yeah? I'd like to see you do it without me.
一丁点问题都没有 老弟
Any time. Any place. Little brother.
如果你坚持这样贫嘴耍帅哗众取宠
If you insist on going through with this idiotic macho stunt,
就别指望我会罩你
you can count me out.
不…等…你要辞职吗
Buh... wai... You're gonna quit?
你不能辞职 你 你被开除了
Well, you can't quit! You... you're fired!
你没法开除我 我已经辞职了
You can't fire me. Because I quit! Humph!
- 妈妈  - 你好 太空游侠
- Hey, Mom!  - Hey, space ranger.
来吧小子 我们去玩飞盘
Come on, boy. Let's go play frisbee.
- 今天回来的真早  - 斯考奇开除我了
- You're home early.  - Scorch fired me.
什么 他怎么能开除你
What? He can't fire you.
我也是这么说的 所以我自己辞职了
That's what I said, so I quit.
所以你在被开除之后辞职了
So you quit after you were fired?
你到底要帮谁
Hey, whose side are you on?
我觉得应该把你们两个关在一起
I think someone should lock the two of you in a room
直到你们学会怎样好好相处
until you figure out how to get along.
他被抓起来才好呢
I hope he gets stranded.
你在干吗 爸爸
What are you doing, Dad?
没什么 我在修旧火箭靴
Uh... Oh, nothing. Just working on the old rocket boots.
好棒 我能帮忙吗
Cool! Can I help?
要子承父业吗 基普
Following in your dad's footsteps, eh, Kipper?
这可是标准的亲子剧情啊
Hey! That makes this an official father-son moment!
这个是干吗用的
What's this do?
当心
Whoa! Look out!
过来了
Aah! Ah, incoming!
盖瑞 浴室里怎么有只火箭靴
Gary! Why is there a rocket boot in our bathroom?
这里是巴卜星电视台
This is BNN.
我们正在直播斯考奇・超新星
We are live as Scorch Supernova investigates
调查来自星际空间的神秘呼救
a mysterious intergalactic cry for help.
本节目由黑暗星球可乐为您提供
Brought to you by Dark Planet Cola.
黑暗星球可乐
Dark Planet Cola!
斯考奇即将走出超新星九号
Scorch is stepping off the Supernova-9 now.
老天 他这身制服可真帅
Oh boy, is he looking good in that suit.
我们来看看黑暗星球表面的直播画面
Oh! Let's go live to the Dark Planet's surface.
这里是斯考奇・超新星 从黑暗星球发回的直播
This is Scorch Supernova, live from the Dark Planet.
我来这里追踪一个星际救援信号
I'm here responding to an intergalactic SOS call,
搜寻无助的受害者
and on the lookout for helpless victims.
切换到遥控摄像机 嘉比
Switching over to remote cams, Gabby.
祝我好运吧
Wish me luck.
本星球最伟大的英雄冒着生命危险…
Our planet's greatest hero, risking life and limb...
他太帅了
He's so awesome.
今后我也要成为斯考奇叔叔这样的人
I'm gonna be just like Uncle Scorch someday.
那我再生一个好了
Well, better have another kid.
盖瑞
Gary.
真是每个父亲都“喜闻乐见”的事啊
Just what every father wants to hear.
我儿子想变成我弟弟那副傻样
My son wants to be like my dim-witted brother.
放心 他只是一时兴奋
Oh, relax. He's excited.
再说 又有什么是斯考奇能给他
Besides, what could Scorch possibly give your son
但你给不了的呢
that you can't?
我将这颗星球献给我的侄子 基普
I dedicate this planet to my nephew, Kip!
我有自己的星球了 超棒
I got my own planet? Awesome!
好吧 这还真是没法比
OK, that's pretty hard to top.
似乎有光源
There appears to be a light source
从一个发亮的地方传过来
coming from a light of some kind.
不不不 别那么做 别往光源处走
Oh, no, no, no. Don't do it! Do not go into the light.
让我们走向光源
Going to the light.
[7-11 日本著名连锁便利店]
太美丽了
It's so beautiful.
发现受害者 救援行动开始
A victim! Commencing rescue op.
你好
Greetings!
我们收到你的呼救 现在过来救你
We've heard your call for help and have come to save you.
我是斯考奇・超新星
I am Scorch Supernova.
奇怪 在我们星球都用握手的
Strange. On my planet we shake hands,
不过就按你的方式来吧
but we can do it your way.
脸都丢尽了
That's humiliating.
老天 你还真爱扭
Boy, you sure love to wave.
我也喜欢 不过我的手臂开始酸了
I love it, too, but my arms are getting tired.
怎么回事
What was that?
什么…
What...?
不
No!
不 撑住
No! Hang on!
看着我 看着我
Look at me. Look at me!
不要死在我面前 兄弟
Don't you die on me, buddy!
不
No!
靠近目标
Moving in.
- 斯考奇  - 我们找到一个蓝家伙
- Scorch!  - We got a blue one!
他不过就是想扭扭而已
All he wanted to do was wave!
[暗指新西兰导演彼得・杰克逊 代表作品《魔戒》]
彼得 杰克逊受伤了
Peter, Jackson is down!
外星人跑到这鸟不拉屎的便利店做什么
Man, what is it with aliens and this desolate roadside 7-Eleven?
站住 外星人
Halt! Alien!
不准用你的先进科技对付我们
Do not use your advanced technology against us!
[暗指美国导演昆汀・塔伦蒂诺 代表作品《低俗小说》]
马蒂 昆汀 行动
Marty, Quentin, move it out!
放马过来吧
Scorch me, baby.
快离开那里
Get out of there!
是时候收拾垃圾了
Time to take out the trash!
下一个谁来
Who's next?
快看他行动
Yeah! Look at him go!
不要 斯考奇麻烦大了
Not now! Scorch is in real trouble.
瞄准这个穿太空服的物体
Aim for the space-suity thingy!
小心
Look out!
是时候撤退了
Time to get outta here.
情况不妙
That's not good.
盖瑞 我们得另寻出路了
Gary, we better find another way outta here.
盖瑞
Gary?
斯考奇
Scorch.
很好 我…
OK, I take...
你们知道吗
You know something?
我爱你们
I love you guys.
欢迎来到地球
Welcome to Earth.
把他绑起来装袋子里 小子们
Tag him and bag him, boys.
巴卜星航空航天管理局已确认
The Baabian Aeronautics and Space Administration have confirmed
与斯考奇・超新星的所有联系均已中断
that all communications with Scorch Supernova have been severed.
依据目前的情况 我们只能推断
At this point, we can only assume
这位本星球最伟大的英雄已经
that our planet's greatest hero is...
死亡
is dead?
对不起 我说不下去了
I'm sorry. I can't do this.
- 不  - 你说他被抓起来才好呢
- Oh, no.  - You said you hoped he got stranded.
你希望发生这种事
You wanted this to happen!
你爸爸不会说那种话的 是吗
I'm sure your father didn't say that. Did you?
我们得去黑暗星球找他
We've gotta get to the Dark Planet and find him!
别急 基普
Just hang on, Kip.
快点 快点 接电话
Come on. Come on, pick up.
你好 盖瑞 你不是辞职了吗
Oh, hello, Gary. I thought you quit.
事态紧急 斯考奇被抓走了
This is important. Scorch has been captured.
- 一切都在我们控制之中  - 拜托
- We've got it under control.  - Come on!
爸爸 斯考奇叔叔让我过去救他
Dad, Uncle Scorch told me to come rescue him.
- 我们就是一支救援队  - 基普
- We can be the rescue team.  - Kip!
我们是他的家人 必须得去救他
We're his family. We need to go save him.
我正在努力解决
I'm doing everything I can.
你根本没努力
You're not doing anything!
只是在打电话
You're talking on the phone!
回你自己房间去
Go to your room.
基普
Kipper?
基普 我知道你想去救他
Kipper, I know you want to rescue him,
你很勇敢
and it's very brave of you.
就算我跟你叔叔经常吵架
Even though your uncle and I fight sometimes,
我们仍然是兄弟
we're still brothers.
我会竭尽所能把他救出来 我保证
And I will do whatever it takes to get him home, I promise you.
我爱你 小子 来抱一个
I love you, buddy. Come on, give us a hug.
基普 基普
Kip? Kip!
琪拉 基普不见了 基普不见了
Kira! Kip's gone! Kip's gone!
- 什么  - 救援舱
- What?  - The rescue pod.
我们得抢在他前面赶到航天局
We've gotta get to BASA before he does.
喂喂喂 你要干什么
Whoa, whoa, whoa. What are you doing?
我们乘火箭靴过去
We're using the rocket boots.
你疯了？回转仪没启动
Are you crazy? The gyroscope is off,
推力装置也坏了
the thrust mechanism is broken.
根本没法用
They're not ready to fly.
我在航天局当了十五年测试飞行员
I spent 15 years as a BASA test pilot.
[英文俚语“高科技”直译“火箭科学”]
这玩意没那么高科技
It's not rocket science.
怎么没有 连名字都叫火箭靴
That's exactly what it is. They're rocket boots!
盖瑞 别顾东顾西了 抓紧
Gary, turn off your brain and hang on.
这样超级无敌危险
This is staggeringly dangerous!
你都不在火箭靴专用道上
You're not even in a rocket boot lane!
小心
Look out!
抱歉
Sorry!
- 你力气太小  - 你想来操纵吗
- So emasculating.  - Do you want to drive?
不 我想活下来
No, I want to live
其实你技术很好
You're actually very good at this!
注意 注意 注意
Look out! Look out! Look out!
抱歉 巴瑞
Sorry, Barry!
我们来了 基普
We're coming, Kipper.
他在哪
Where is he?
基普 别 基普 不要
Kip! No, Kipper, no!
基普 停下
Kip, stop!
- 基普 看上面  - 基普 不要
- Kip, up here!  - Kipper, please!
距自动发射还剩六十秒
Automated launch in T-minus 60 seconds.
基普 看这里
Kip, up here!
盖瑞 当心
Gary, look out.
这主意坏透了
This is a bad idea.
妈妈 爸爸 你们一起来吗
Mom! Dad! Are you coming?
不 宝贝 这可不是闹着玩的
No, honey, this isn't a game.
卡住了
It's stuck!
盖瑞 想想办法
Gary, do something!
我来取消发射
I'll shut down the launch.
十二 十一
Twelve, eleven...
你选择了终止发射
You've chosen Terminate Launch.
- 若要确认 请说“是”  - 是
- To confirm, say yes.  - Yes.
- 你说“香蕉” 是吗  - 不是
- You said "Banana." Is that correct?  - No.
- 你回答“不是”  - 盖瑞 快点
- You replied "No. "  - Gary, hurry up!
取消终止发射进程
Terminate Launch canceled.
不是 我想说“是”
No. I mean yes!
- 到底是“是”还是“不是”  - 不是
- Is that a yes or a no?  - No.
- 你说了“是”吗  - 是
- Did you say yes?  - Yes!
你说了“是” 还是…
Yes, you said yes, or...?
是 是
Yes! Yes!
卡住了
It's stuck!
抱歉 盖瑞
Sorry, Gary.
你是对终止发射说“是”吗
Did you say yes to Terminate Launch?
是
Yes!
发射已终止
Launch terminated.
真险
That was close.
基普 你把我吓坏了
Oh, Kip, you scared me.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我答应了斯考奇叔叔要去救他
I promised Uncle Scorch I'd go save him.
以后再也不要这样做了
Don't you ever do that again.
不 基普是对的
No. Kip's right.
斯考奇是我弟弟
Scorch is my brother.
- 亲爱的  - 我得去救他
- Honey?  - I've gotta go save him.
等等 你要做什么
Wait. What are you doing?
很好 发射程序已恢复
Excellent. Launch sequence reengaged.
盖瑞
Gary?
- 爸爸  - 我爱你们
- Dad!  - I love you guys!
- 爸爸  - 盖瑞
- Dad!  - Gary!
莉娜 我需要你帮忙
Lena, I need your help.
- 琪拉  - 盖瑞上了救援舱
- Kira!  - Gary was on that pod!
别担心 他一着陆我们就跟他联系
Don't worry. We'll make contact as soon as he lands.
不不不 你必须派个人跟着他
No, no, no. You have to send someone after him.
没什么是我“必须”做的
I don't have to do anything.
你发号施令的时代已经过去了
You don't give the orders around here anymore.
盖瑞一个人绝对活不下来
Gary will never survive out there alone.
求求你 把我爸爸救回来
Please, bring my dad back.
别担心 小朋友 我们会竭尽所能
Don't worry, little guy. We're doing everything we can.
我能帮上什么忙吗
What can I do to help?
是你自己选择做全职妈妈的
You're the one who wanted to be a stay-at-home mom.
那就好好待在家 别来妨碍我工作
So why don't you stay at home and let me do my job.
准备最终推进 盖瑞
Prepare for final approach, Gary.
系好安全带
Fasten your seatbelt.
[汽车电影院]
《来自太空 3D》
这电影不应该是3D的吗
I thought this movie was supposed to be in 3-D.
的确是3D的
Shh. It is in 3-D.
这下好多了
OK, that's better.
四十八区
Area 48.
四十九区
Area 49.
五十区
Area 50.
起落架已放
Landing gear deployed.
起落架已毁
Landing gear destroyed.
请小心离开机舱 盖瑞
Please exit with caution, Gary.
飞行中舱内物件可能发生移动
Contents may have shifted during the flight.
乱七八糟 是吧
It's all over the place, isn't it?
没事 别慌 想想训练时怎么学的
OK, OK, don't panic. Remember your training.
最安全的做法就是在机舱里等待
The safest thing to do is wait in your pod.
自毁程序启动
Self-destruct sequence initiated
什么 自毁 你是个救援舱
What? Self-destruct? You're a rescue pod!
救援舱不能自毁
Rescue pods don't self-destruct.
- 这一艘就能 盖瑞  - 太荒唐了
- This one does, Gary.  - This is ridiculous!
- 二十九 二十八 二十七  - 来人啊 救命
- Twenty-nine, 28, 27...  - Hey, anybody! Help!
你的计划就是崩溃吗 盖瑞
Is that your plan, Gary? Panicking?
- 十六 十五  - 拜托
- Sixteen, 15...  - Come on!
赶快 盖瑞 你快没时间了
Ticktock, Gary. Come on. You're running out of time.
- 水上降落 怪物袭击  - 十 九
- Water landing, monster attack... Aha!  - Ten, nine...
- 傻傻困在舱里  - 八 七
- Foolishly trapped inside pod!  - eight, seven...
[打碎玻璃]
- 傻傻困在舱里  - 八 七
- Foolishly trapped inside pod!  - eight, seven...
六 五
six, five...
开始崩溃吧
Time to panic.
三 二
three, two...
一 要炸了
one. We're toast.
这套衣服的科技含量惊人
Ah... the technology in this suit is incredible.
- 打开它  - 遵命 长官
- Now open it.  - Yes, sir.
恶心
Yuck!
终极蓝核
Blubonium.
威力比原子能还要强上万倍
Ten thousand times more powerful than atomic energy.
那玩意怎么会在里面
Hey. How'd that get in there?
你醒了
Oh, you're awake.
放开我 让我离开
Let me go! Let me outta here!
继续睡吧
Shh. Go back to sleep.
您正在收听C段调频的超凡极右时间
You're listening to Far-out, Far-right Hour on C-Dub FM.
下面接通热线电话 您好
Let's go to the phones! Caller?
我是霍克 在五十一区的七一一便利店上班
This is Hawk calling. I work at 7-Eleven near Area 51,
等了这么多年 终于实现了
and after years of waiting, it finally happened!
找到女朋友了？
You had a date with a girl.
什么 不 是外星人 老兄
What? No. A close-encounter, man!
我们看向窗外
We looked out the window
那个蓝色的家伙就站在那里
and this blue dude was standing right there.
- 太棒了  - 霍克 霍克 听我说
- It was awesome.  - Hawk, Hawk, Hawk, listen to me.
如果你说的是真的
If what you say is true,
那他们来地球就只有一个目的
they're here for one reason and one reason only,
绑架
abduction!
没事 哥们 我们是朋友
It's OK, bro! We're friends.
- 你在干什么  - 要给他留个好印象
- What are you doing?  - We gotta make a good impression.
拿出点和平的诚意来
We need a peace offering.
没事的 小兄弟
It's OK, little guy.
欢迎来到地球 蓝哥们
Welcome to Earth, blue buddy.
为了防止奴役人类的行为
In an effort to avoid enslavement,
我赠予你人类最美味的冰凉醒脑饮品
I offer you the finest chilled refreshment known to the human race.
他喜欢
He likes it!
他当然喜欢 对你的品牌有点信心
Of course he likes it. Where's your brand loyalty, man?
不
No!
你会后悔的 别喝那么急
You're gonna regret it! Don't do it!
没事没事 冷静点 蓝哥们 没事的
OK, OK, OK. Calm down, blue buddy. It's OK.
这叫冰上头
It's called a brain freeze.
跟我们在一起 就要学会小口吸
If you're gonna hang with us, you need to learn to sip.
带他走
Take him away!
- 放我下去  - 小蓝哥们
- Put me down!  - Little blue buddy...
[51种口味]
[没有哪里比51区更好玩]
[管制区域]
[未经批准 严禁进入]
[51区]
停下来 放我出去
Stop this! Let me out!
[美国全球防御局为您呈现51区全方位解答]
[欢迎来到地球]
异世界的生物 欢迎来到地球
Hello, creature from another world. Welcome to planet Earth.
你现在是美国政府的客人了
You are now a guest of the US government.
地球上的居民又称作“人类”
When interacting with the inhabitants of Earth, or humans,
与他们互动时须遵守以下基本礼节
you should abide by the following basic etiquette.
可以握手
Handshake, good.
不可以用死亡光线蒸发人类
Death ray... bad. No vaporizing.
现代人类文明还禁止以下下几点
Modern Earth culture also frowns on the followings.
吃人肉 插“菊花” 银色连体裤
Eating human flesh, probing, silver jumpsuits,
绑架人类 共产主义 赤身裸体
abduction, Communism, nudity.
如果你或你认识的人
If you or someone you know
建造了金字塔
is responsible for building the pyramids,
请告知我们
we'd like to know about it.
如果你去过百慕大三角
If you've been to the Bermuda Triangle
还顺手带走了几个人类
and brought someone home with you,
请立即归还
please return them immediately.
最后 如果你是外星长住居民
And, finally, if you're a resident alien,
请去一百三十六层的移民处柜台登记
please report to the immigration desk on level 316.
希望这段录像能让您了解我们的星球
We hope this has been an informative look at our planet,
请不要对我们发动战争
and urge you not to seek war against us.
希望您在五十一区过得愉快
Enjoy your stay here at Area 51.
[剧 终]
来瞧一瞧你的脑袋
Let's take a peek into that head of yours.
大脑扫描处理中
Brain scan processing.
愚蠢 呆傻 迟钝 一般
Stupid. Simple. Dimwit. Average.
聪明 天才 天才 天才
Smart. Genius. Genius. Genius...
我们逮着一个真天才
We got ourselves a real genius!
沙克会想见你的
Shanker's gonna want to meet you.
这就是那个奇才 长官
Here's the brainiac, sir.
你就是那个天才
So... you're the genius.
你要怎么样 研究我？解剖我？
What are you gonna do to me? Probe me? Dissect me?
- 把我剁碎吃掉？ - 放松
- Chop me up and eat me?  - Relax.
我喜欢你的发明
I'm a big fan of your work.
斯考奇
Scorch!
你把我弟弟怎么了
What have you done with my brother?
我们马上就会说到他的
We'll get to him soon enough.
这是你设计的吧
This is your design, isn't it?
你怎么知道
How do you know that?
很让我印象深刻
Well, color me impressed.
我自认是外星科技的内行
And I consider myself a connoisseur when it comes to alien technology.
你的才智可以为我所用
I could use a man with your brain power.
盖瑞 我这里是劳动释放制度
You see, Gary, I run a work release program.
你劳动 我就释放你
You work, then I release you.
你要确保我最新的项目能顺利进行
You are going to make sure my latest project goes off without a hitch.
见到斯考奇之前我什么也不会做
I'm not doing anything until I see Scorch.
在我动真格之前你就尽管得瑟吧
You can whine till you're blue in the face,
这里的一切都是我说了算
but I call the shots around here.
全体出去 快速前进
Everyone out, now! Double-time!
等等 还没说完呢 我弟弟在哪里
Wait! Wait! We're not finished! Where's my brother?
你好 沙克小亲亲
Hello, Shanky-panky.
你好 我的宝贝
Hello, my darling.
你美极了
You look ravishing.
你总是这么说
Oh, you always say that.
因为事实如此
That's because it's true.
- 礼物收到了吗  - 嗯
- Did you get my present?  - Yes.
- 收到了  - 喜欢吗
- I did.  - So do you like it?
还…行吧
It's... OK.
宝贝 怎么了
Pookie, what's wrong?
没事 挺好的 只是我以为会有更多
Nothing, it's fine. I just... I was expecting more.
那只是个样品
Well, that was just a sample
还有很多 我保证
There's more coming, I promise.
我带来的足够我们一起统治宇宙
I'm bringing enough so we can rule the universe together.
抓紧 亲爱的
Hurry, my love.
轻点 轻点 慢慢把我放下
Gentle, gentle. Just set me down nice and easy.
喂 有人吗
Hello? Anyone?
你们不能这样 我有人权的
You can't do this! I know my rights!
你好 室友
Hey! Hi there, roomie!
马桶你用完了吗
Hey, are you finished with the toilet?
我叫瑟曼 很高兴认识你
I'm Thurman. Pleased to meet you.
天哪 你浑身都是黏液
Hello. Oh, my goodness. You're all covered in slime.
- 你都干透了  - 现在不干了
- Ugh! You're all dried out.  - Not anymore.
我来自加德布鲁克四七五星
I'm from Zaddlebrok 475.
- 没听过  - 听过加德布鲁克四七三吧
- Never heard of it.  - You've heard of Zaddlebrok 473.
- 对对 当然听过  - 再过两个星就是
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, of course.  - It's two planets over.
有道理
Makes sense.
总之 你先安顿一下
Anyway, you should settle in.
东西放在下铺就行
Throw your stuff on the bottom bunk.
我得逃出去
I gotta get outta here.
不能打个电话吗
Don't I get a phone call?
是啊 打电话 宽屏电视
Oh, yeah. A phone call? A big-screen TV?
埃及纯棉床单
Egyptian cotton sheets?
这里是五十一区 老兄 醒醒吧
This is Area 51, man. Wake up!
小点声 我要闭一眼
Keep it down! I'm trying to get some shut-eye.
我懂了 闭一眼 你只有一只眼
Oh, I get it. Shut-eye. You've got one eye.
你拿我的一只眼开玩笑？
Are you making fun of my one eye?
冷静 独眼妹 别忘了这里的制度
Easy, Io. Remember the program.
坚持制度 坚持制度
Just stick to the program, stick to the program.
抱歉我突然发火了
I apologize for my outburst.
我叫独眼妹 我有些情绪问题要克服
My name is lo, and I'm working through some anger issues.
她人很好
She seems nice.
是个好姑娘 我是医生
Oh, yeah, great gal. I'm Doc.
- 你是个医生？ - 电台脱口秀治疗师
- You're a doctor?  - Radio talk show therapist.
跟真医生没区别 就是所有资格证都没有
Same thing without all the training, credentials or qualifications.
小蓝兄弟 你叫什么
So, Little Boy Blue, you got a name?
盖瑞 我来找我弟弟 你见过他吗
Gary. I'm here looking for my brother. Have you seen him?
他长什么样 跟你一样蓝吗
What's he look like? Blue like you?
一点不错 但他肌肉健美发达
Yes, exactly like me except with huge muscles
脸廓硬朗刚毅 牙齿整齐洁白
and a chiseled jaw and perfect teeth.
好吧 就是说你是比较丑的那个
OK, so you're the ugly brother.
我应该不会那么说的
Oh, well, I wouldn't put it that way.
我又不是在问你
Oh, it's not a question.
斯考奇可以帮助我们逃离
Look, Scorch can bust us out of here.
他有架飞船 他可以带我们回家
He's got a ship. He can get us home.
只有一个办法能离开这里
There's only one way out of here.
发明够酷的玩意 沙克才会放你走
Invent enough cool stuff and Shanker lets you go.
这就是五十一区的制度
That's how Area 51 works.
他诱拐了我们这些宇宙内最聪明的外星人
He lures the smartest aliens from across the universe
把我们关进监狱
and throws us in jail.
比如瑟曼 他以前是位教授
Take Thurman. He was a professor.
他用那四只手发明了触屏科技
Those four hands invented touchscreen technology.
还有独眼妹 她过去是名图书管理员
Or Io. She used to be a librarian.
她实在吃不消天天帮人找书
She got so mad looking stuff up for people
于是发明了搜索引擎
that she invented the search engine.
最重要的是 我
And most importantly, me.
我的电台秀出名之后 我发明了社交网络
After my radio show got famous, I invented social networking.
我有五十亿等待通过的好友请求
I've got five billion pending friend requests.
沙克就是这样得到此地的运转资金的
That's how Shanker bankrolls this place.
他窃取我们的科技对外出售
He rips off our technology and sells it to the world.
无缝不钻无孔不入
He's got deals with everybody.
苹果 脸书 谷歌那帮人
Apple, Facebook, them Google guys.
你以为人类能做出这些东西吗
You think humans could build this stuff?
我不这么认为
I don't think so.
你以为是谁发明了网络
Who do you think invented the Internet?
手机 电脑动画？
Cell phones? Computer animation?
是我们
We did!
谢谢 我很喜欢科技史 但我在找我弟弟
Thank you. I love tech history. But have you seen my brother?
外星人注意 请立即到餐厅集合
Attention, aliens. Please report immediately to the cafeteria.
记住
And remember,
禁止在走廊里漂浮
levitating in the passageways is strictly prohibited.
那是什么鬼东西
What the heck is that?
全宇宙只有一个生物呼噜能打这么响
There is only one creature in the universe that snores that loud.
斯考奇 斯考奇 醒醒
Scorch! Scorch! Wake up!
今天有太空英雄考试 没复习
Space hero test today. Didn't study.
什么玩意
What the...?
睡个觉要用掉一整盘沙拉
Needs a whole salad to sleep.
盖瑞 盖瑞 你在这里干什么
Ow! Huh? Gary? Hey, Gary! What are you doing here?
我来救你
I'm here to rescue you.
你来救我？我肯定还在做梦
You're rescuing me? I'm still dreaming.
我提心吊胆跑了十五光年来救你
I come 15 light-years out of my comfort zone to save you,
我的亲弟弟就是这么谢我的
and this is the thanks I get from my own brother?
叫我前老板 我把你开除了
Try ex-boss. I fired you.
不 我辞职了
No, I quit.
第一次没有我的任务就被关进监狱了
And your first mission without me, you wind up in jail.
你又在哪里呢 监狱
And where did you end up? Jail.
你们俩应该来预约治疗
You two should make an appointment.
外星人注意 餐厅现在开始供应午餐
Attention, aliens. Lunch is now being served in the cafeteria.
请留神大兵 他们特别心不在焉
Please be mindful of the joes as they are unusually sloppy.
发射台电脑会告诉我们爸爸的位置
The launch station computer will tell us where Daddy is.
定位十三号救援舱
Locate Rescue Pod 13.
已于二十九点整自毁
Self-destruct initiated at 2900 hours
- 什么  - 自毁？
- What?  - Self-destruct?
回放舱内录像
Play back in-flight camera.
你是个救援舱 救援舱不能自毁
You're a rescue pod! Rescue pods don't self-destruct.
太荒唐了
This is ridiculous!
爸爸
Dad!
只有指挥中心才能摧毁飞船
Only Mission Control can destroy a ship.
一定是这里的人发出的指令
Somebody here had to give that order.
快趴下
Quick, get down.
莉娜
Lena.
别动
Keep still.
行 很好
OK, that's good.
- 快点装货  - 明白 老大
- Hurry up and get it loaded.  - You got it, boss.
这么多终极蓝核足够炸掉整个银河系
That much Blubonium could blow up the whole galaxy.
- 酷  - 不不不 一点也不酷
- Cool.  - No, no, no, not cool.
非常非常不酷 我们得通知…
Very, very not cool. We have to tell somebody.
通知谁
Tell somebody what?
莉娜
Lena!
快跑
Run!
快逃 基普
Go, Kipper!
放开我
Let me go!
我明明让你回家的 亲爱的
I gave you a chance to go home, sweetie.
你自己非要留下
You should've taken it.
小崽子跑掉了
Little rat got away.
没关系
It doesn't matter,
不过是个小屁孩
he's just a kid.
把她绑起来带走
Tie her up and bring her with us.
等等 盖瑞怎么办
Wait! What about Gary?
盖瑞 那个懦夫
Gary? That coward?
他再也回不来了
He's never coming back.
谢谢
Thank you.
给我来点抖抖果冻
Hit me with some jiggly cubes.
各位先生
Hi, guys.
不知道你们到底是先生
Not sure if you guys are guys.
还是女士
Or ladies.
不论如何 没关系
Either way, no problem.
这些是小灰人
Those are the Greys.
不知道沙克抓住了他们什么把柄
No one knows what Shank has got on them,
他们对他言听计从
but they do his bidding.
所以千万别惹毛他们 懂吗
So don't get on their bad side, understand?
你们好 大光头
What's up? Eggheads.
每样都来两份 再随便来一份什么
Give me two of everything and one more of anything.
有些东西就是与生俱来的
Hey! Some things you just can't teach.
这些都是什么
What are... what is all this?
这里有各种外星佳肴
We have lots of alien delicacies.
怪味果 九爪鱼
Blorm, Phrebbish,
包子 减肥包子
Zumft, diet Zumft,
放养的包子
free-range Zumft,
非乳制无麸包子
non-dairy gluten-free Zumft.
如果想要更完美的味觉体验
And if you're looking for something a bit more refined,
这里还有新鲜的土豆泥
we got fresh plarbe.
你好啊
Oh, hello.
实际上 我还不饿
You know what? I'm not hungry.
- 外星佬  - 您先请
- Aliens.  - After you.
盖瑞 我看过一堆越狱电影
Gary! I've seen a lot of jail break movies.
我们只需要分散他们注意力
All we need to break out of here is a diversion,
找把铲子
a shovel
另外我们一定不要声张
and a blowup dummy of ourselves.
没那么简单 斯考奇 别这么没头脑
It's not that simple, Scorch. Don't be reckless.
从现在起压低声音讨论越狱大计
And from now on, let's whisper our escape plan.
这就是你的毛病 盖瑞
That's your problem, Gary.
总是幻想连篇
Always wishy-washy,
从不付诸行动
never taking action.
这就是为什么我成了英雄
That's what makes me the heroic brother.
你算什么英雄
You're some hero.
没有我 你什么都不是
Without me, you're nothing.
听啊 电脑乖乖男大言不惭
Ooh, big words from a computer-loving mama's boy.
不 这叫忠言逆耳
No, they're regular-sized words.
你这么笨又怎么能明白呢
You're just too dumb to understand.
幸好基普将想成为我这样的英雄
Good thing Kip's gonna be a hero like me,
而不是你这样的懦夫
not a coward like you.
还给你
Ugh! You take that back!
干得好 盖瑞 真是“成熟”
Oh! Nice, Gary. Nice. Real mature.
正中目标
Oh! Right in the kisser!
食物大战
Food fight!
餐厅发生食物大骚乱
We have a food-related disturbance in the cafeteria!
- 捉住他  - 站住 给我过来
- Get him!  - Stop! Get back here!
过来 小畜生
Come here, you little runt!
真是风水轮流转呢
How the tables have turned.
真是走运
Well, that was lucky.
马上住手 不然会有人受伤的
Stop this right now before somebody gets hurt.
好吧 你自找的
All right, that's it.
正中红心
Bull's eye!
开打了
Oh, it's on!
看看你闯的祸
Now you've done it.
[暗指美国影星布鲁斯・威利斯 代表作品《虎胆龙威》]
布鲁斯 当心
Bruce, look out!
威利斯 快逃
Willis, run!
大伙儿 这也太不礼貌了
People, people, where are your manners?
吃东西的时候说话才是最不礼貌的
You're the one talking with your mouth full of yourself.
你非得火上浇油吗
Do you have to do that now?
抓紧一切时间练习
Hey, practice makes perfect.
乔治 卢卡斯 上啊
George! Lucas! Let's go!
[暗指美国导演乔治・卢卡斯 代表作品《星球大战》]
- 军警来了  - 抓住他们
- It's the fuzz!  - Get 'em!
[暗指英裔美国导演克里斯托弗・诺兰 代表作品《记忆碎片》]
克里斯托弗 诺兰 给我站起来
Christopher! Nolan! On your feet!
你好 亲爱的
Hello, my dear.
马上住手
Stop right there!
你竟敢刮指挥官耳光子
How dare you slap a commanding officer!
行了 外星人
All right, alien...
斯考奇 小心身后
Scorch, behind you!
- 好球  - 谢谢
- Nice!  - Thank you.
猜猜我是谁
Guess who!
我们离开这里
Let's get outta here.
好样的
Oh, yeah!
立正
Ten-hut!
[恶搞泰坦尼克号中杰克在船头怒吼]
我是宇宙之王
I'm king of the world!
没打中
You missed.
我警告过他们不要玩食物大战
I told these guys, "You'd better not food fight,"
但他们不听
But they did.
我会打扫干净的
I'm gonna sweep this up.
到和平防御盾集合 快速行进
Report to the peace shield, on the double.
这就是和平防御盾
This is the peace shield.
是一把行星枪
It's an asteroid gun.
一把巨枪并不能带来和平吧
Nothing says peace like a giant gun, huh?
打死我也理解不了
It's overkill if you ask me.
但这是美国啊
But it's America.
他们就是爱夸大其词
They supersize everything.
这是你们造出来的吗
You guys built this thing?
搞了差不多十年
Took us almost ten years.
现在只差动力装置了
Now we're just waiting for one last piece. The power source.
然后我们就能回母星了
Then we can go back to our home planets.
- 回太阳  - 回太阳
- Or sun.  - Or sun.
真的吗 你住在太阳上？
Seriously? You live on the sun?
没错 气候难以忍受
Yep. You can't beat the weather.
虽然你没有参与设计
Oh, even though you didn't work on it,
也在这里签个名吧
you've gotta sign the floor.
一切为了粉丝
Anything for a fan.
这么多名字
That's a lot of names.
他们都去哪儿了
Where are all those guys?
沙克建这机器已很多年了
Shanker's been building this thing for years.
他可能让他们走了
He probably let 'em go.
拿开你的脏手
Get your hands off me.
你逃不掉的
You'll never get away with this.
现实真美好
The beauty of it is,
我已经逃掉了
I already have.
斯考奇和盖瑞都不在了
With Scorch and Gary gone,
谁还能阻止我呢
who's gonna stop me?
什么情…
What the...?
是时候收拾垃圾了
Time to take out the trash!
- 基普 不要  - 放马过来吧
- Kipper, no!  - Scorch me, baby!
给我过来
Come back here!
- 放开我妈妈  - “放马过来吧”
- Let my mom go!  - "Scorch me, baby."
你这个怪物
You monster!
要是有相机就好了
I wish I had my camera.
多完美的家族肖像
What a perfect family portrait.
快速行进 将军就要来了
Look alive! General's coming in hot!
别做傻事
Shh. Don't do anything stupid.
五十一区的全体士兵
Soldiers of Area 51,
最后的难题已迎刃而解
the final piece of the puzzle has arrived.
终极蓝核反应堆
That's a Blubonium reactor.
他怎么搞到手的
How did he get his hands on it?
有人偷偷塞到我制服里了
Somebody smuggled that thing in my suit.
有什么大不了的
What's the big deal?
你知不知道那玩意儿威力有多大
Do you have any idea how powerful that stuff is?
准备试发射
Prepare for test firing.
- 你们听到了  - 动起来
- You heard the man!  - Go! Go! Go!
[危险]
我的老朋友 哈雷彗星
My old friend, Halley's Comet.
五十年后也回不来了
Not back for another 50 years.
到时候谁会想念它呢
So... who's gonna miss it?
瞄准哈雷彗星
Targeting Halley's Comet.
为哈雷的家人准备吊唁信
Preparing condolence card for Halley's family.
目标锁定
Target acquired.
永别了 哈雷
Hasta la vista, Halley.
太好了 成功了
Yeah, baby! It works!
我们能回家了
We're going home!
酷毙了
Awesome!
火辣一击
Hot diggity!
大事不妙
This is not good.
伙计们 开心点 来庆祝一下
Come on, guys, lighten up. It's party time!
不要闷闷不乐了
Get down with your bad self!
那个装置里的终极蓝核足以毁掉一个星球
There's enough Blubonium in that thing to blow up a planet.
我们是要像你一样磨叽到死
Well, are we gonna sit around "Garying" this to death
还是真正行动起来
or are we gonna do something about it?
斯考奇
Scorch!
- 你疯了吗  - 把它放下 马上
- Are you nuts?  - Put that down, now!
抓住他
Get him!
你死定了
You're going down!
[暗指加拿大导演詹姆斯・卡梅隆 代表作品《魔鬼终结者》]
詹姆斯 卡梅隆 抓住他
James, Cameron, get the alien!
放马过来吧
Scorch me, baby.
做好准备 伙计们
Brace yourself, boys!
拦住他
Stop him!
他耍得你们团团转
He's walking all over you.
截住他
Stop him!
哥这招怎么样
How you like me now?
不 我的反应堆
No! My reactor!
把他带走
Get him out of here!
- 不 住手  - 盖瑞 别插手
- No, stop!  - Gary, stay out of this!
把小的也带上
Bring the little one, too.
你这样正中他下怀 盖瑞
You got him right where you want him, Gary!
如果修不好反应堆
If you can't fix that reactor,
你们就再也别想回家了
nobody's going home. Ever.
他无声的怒气比爆发的怒气更可怕
His quiet anger is even angrier than his loud one.
你这个没用的蓝白痴
You useless blue moron.
你知不知道你刚刚干了些什么
Do you realize what you've done?
救了几百万无辜的外星人
I saved millions of innocent aliens,
因为我是英雄
'cause that's what heroes do.
你邪恶的计划没有得逞
You failed at your evil plans,
因为你是恶棍
'cause that's what villains do.
这块面包屑粘在我脸上
And this crumb got stuck on my face,
因为这是面包屑
'cause that's what crumbs do.
- 斯考奇  - 没事 盖瑞
- Scorch.  - It's OK, Gary.
不论你怎么处置我
Do what you want with me.
我都不会帮你
I'll never help you.
我就知道你会这么说
I thought you might say that.
斯考奇 不要
Scorch! No!
- 有遗言吗  - 有
- Any last words?  - Yes.
朋友们 异星人们 同胞们
Friends, aliens, countrymen,
请高举你们的触手
lend me your tentacles.
不要把我看作是英雄
Don't think of me as a hero.
请把我看做是个行为英勇的英雄主义者
Think of me as a guy who acted heroically while full of heroism.
你练了多久了
Have you been practicing this?
盖瑞 帮我告诉嘉比我爱她
Gary, tell Gabby I love her.
告诉我的粉丝我爱他们
Tell my fans I love them.
总之 要是有人问起
Just as a general rule, if anyone asks,
就说我爱他们
tell them I love them.
盖瑞 我也爱你 老弟
Hey, Gary, I love you too, little brother.
- 永别了 残忍的银河系  - 不
- Goodbye, cruel galaxy.  - No!
看来我还有时间多说几句
Well, looks like I've got time for a few more.
那个给我的飞船打蜡的家伙
Tell the guy that waxes my ship...
他叫什么来着
what's his name again?
随便吧
It doesn't matter.
告诉他我爱他
Just tell him that I love him.
告诉黑暗星球可乐公司的人
And the people at Dark Planet Cola,
我也爱他们
tell them I love them.
闭嘴 知道了
Stop. We get it.
不 住手
No. Stop!
我是航天局工程师
I'm a BASA engineer.
我可以修好反应堆
I can fix the Blubonium.
不要帮他 盖瑞
Don't help him, Gary!
我们才是正义一方
We did the right thing!
不要
No!
不 斯考奇 放他出来
No! Scorch! Let him go!
只要你帮我修好和平防御盾
As soon as you fix my peace shield.
还有一件事
Oh, and one more thing.
要是你胆敢向其他人透露一句
If you tell any of the others about this,
我就把你们全部冻住
I'll freeze you all!
滚进去 外星佬
Get in there, alien.
搞出这种乱子 你居然还有脸回来
You got some nerve walking in here after that stunt.
我…
I...
你弟弟呢
Where's your brother?
被沙克抓住了
Shanker's got him.
他为什么放了你
Why'd he let you go?
因为他觉得我能修好
Because he thinks I can fix it.
那你行吗
Can you fix it?
当然 我可是航天局工程师
Of course. I'm a BASA engineer.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank goodness.
但我觉得我不该帮他
But I don't think I should.
什么
Say what?
修好了 我们就能回家
I fix it, we all go home,
是吗
right?
正是 有什么不对吗
Exactly. What's wrong with that?
沙克就会拥有宇宙内最强大的武器
Shanker ends up with the most powerful weapon in the universe.
无非是一支玩具枪射射小行星
So he's got a toy for shooting down asteroids.
有什么大不了
Big deal.
你也看到它的威力了
You saw what it can do.
谁知道下次轮到哪个星球
Who knows what he'll blow up next.
要是你的星球怎么办
What if it's your planet?
别瞎紧张 盖瑞
Don't be paranoid, Gary.
天才总是这样紧张兮兮的
It happens to smart people all the time.
太多的思绪会吞噬掉你的才智
You start thinking too much and it gets the best of you.
你们真的相信沙克吗
You guys actually trust Shanker?
我们并没有选择的权利
We're kinda low on options here, gary.
我们还能怎么办
What choice do we have?
我们可以拒绝
We refuse to fix it.
然后呢 静坐抗议吗
Then what? Stage a silent protest?
别开玩笑了
Come on, man!
你想让我们一辈子困在这里吗
You want us to be stuck in here forever?
我也不知道该怎么办
I don't know what to do, OK?
让我静一静 思考一下
Just let me sit down for a second and think!
你这是静静地等死
You mean sit around and do nothing.
总之我们要去修好它
Well, we're gonna try to fix it.
你到底加不加入
Are you coming or not?
告诉你 我们不需要你
You know what? We don't need you.
我们走 瑟曼
Come on, Thurman.
剪红线
Cut the red wire.
不不不 剪绿线
No, no, no! Cut the green wire.
当我没说 我是色盲
Scratch that. I'm colorblind.
闭嘴 我需要集中精力
Quiet! I need to concentrate.
我的第三只眼太干扰视线
My third eye, it's messing me up.
我不干了
I can't do it!
就这样了 玩完了？
So that's it? Game over?
全体远离终极蓝核
Step away from the Blubonium.
专业的来了
My man!
瑟曼 你被开除了
Thurman, you're fired.
你知道应该怎么做吗
You sure you know what you're doing?
我在银河工程师考试中拿到十二点零的高分
I scored a 12.0 on my galactic engineering exams.
你知道这代表什么吗
Do you know what that means?
代表你在高中没有朋友？
You had no friends in high school?
代表在一个满是书呆子的银河系里
It means in a galaxy filled with nerds,
我是书呆之王
I'm their king.
希望能行
I hope this works.
- 能回家了  - 我要去交停车罚单了
- We're going home!  - It's time to pay my parking tickets!
盖瑞 这正常吗
Uh, Gary? Is that normal?
- 好了 瑟曼 别瞎紧张  - 好吧
- Come on, Thurman, don't be paranoid.  - OK.
盖瑞 盖瑞 盖瑞
Gary! Gary! Gary...!
说几句吧 盖瑞
Speech, Gary!
收拾行李 准备出发
Pack your stuff and be ready to go.
我要去把我弟弟救出来
I'm going to get my brother back.
- 这家伙想见你 长官  - 我来处理
- This one was asking for you, sir.  - Leave him with me.
我来带我弟弟走
I'm here for my brother.
盖瑞 终于肯合作了
Ah, Gary... finally a team player.
我按你的要求做了 修好了反应堆
I did what you asked. I fixed the reactor.
而且很及时
And just in time.
有了这些终极蓝核 我会有多强大呢
Imagine how powerful I'll be with all this Blubonium.
- 你是怎么…  - 你们自称是智能生命
- What? How did you...?  - You call yourself intelligent life.
太有意思了
These are fun.
我可以玩一整天
I could do that all day.
放我们走 你已经得偿所愿了
Let us go! You got what you wanted!
为什么要放你们走 反正迟早要杀死你们
Why let you go now, only to hunt you down later?
杀死我们？但我们为和平而来
Hunt us down? But we come in peace.
没有人为和平而来
Nobody comes in peace.
我六岁那年眼睁睁看着他们杀死我爸爸
I was six years old when they took my father from me.
[译注：著名外星人事件发生地]
新墨西哥州罗斯维尔市 1947年
想想看 小子
Think about this, champ.
宇宙中有那么多星球
With that many stars out there,
一定有智能生命的存在
there just has to be intelligent life.
- 好棒 能让我看看吗  - 马上 儿子
- Golly! Can I have a look, Pops?  - In a minute, son.
什么 那是什么
What? What is that?
我的天啊 是飞碟
Good gravy! It's a UFO!
你是不是忘记加油了？
我以为你去加油了！我只带了零食！
儿子 真是不敢相信
Son, you wouldn't believe it!
我这辈子都在等待这一…
This is the moment I've been waiting for my entire...
不
No!
在你和你弟弟团聚之前
Before you join your brother,
我还有最后一样东西给你看
there's one last thing I'd like to show you.
[美国军方对于同性恋者的原则，此处Gary误以为Shanker要对他出柜]
我懂 不要问 不要说
Hey, don't ask, don't tell.
[美国军方对于同性恋者的原则，此处Gary误以为Shanker要对他出柜]
我不是说头发 蠢货
Not the hair, you idiot.
- 莉娜  - 你好 盖瑞
- Lena!  - Ugh. Hello, Gary.
你已经见过我的未婚夫了
I see you've met my fianc?
- 未婚夫  - 我们在网上认识的
- Fianc?  - We met online.
你得跟上潮流 盖瑞
Get with the times, Gary.
你们全家都那么喜欢多管闲事
Your whole family has been meddling in my business.
- 诀别的时候到了 盖瑞  - 基普 琪拉
- Time to say goodbye, Gary.  - Kip! Kira!
- 莉娜 他在利用你  - 他利用了所有人
- Lena, please, he's using you.  - He's using all of us.
他只是嫉妒你不爱他而已
OK, he's just jealous he couldn't have you.
- 什么  - 拜拜
- Hmm?  - Ta-ta.
你怎么能这样做
How could you do this?
你觉得我真会爱上一个外星人吗
You think I'm actually in love with an alien?
等她带着我的终极蓝核离开你们的星球之后
When she leaves your planet with my Blubonium,
我就会炸了它
I'm gonna blow it up.
这还只是开始
But Baab's just the beginning.
我要把这些异类星球一个个消灭掉
I'm gonna wipe out the alien infestation one planet at a time.
如果你摧毁所有的智能生命星球
If you destroy every planet with intelligent life,
天空中就没有星星了
you'll have no stars left in the sky.
我早就过了看星星的年龄了
My stargazing days are over.
放我出去
Let me out!
恭喜 你自由了 才怪
Hey, congratulations. You're free! Not!
不 你们不能这样
No, you can't do this!
拜托 放我出去
Please! Let me out of here!
不知道你能不能听到 但…对不起
I don't know if you can hear me, but... I'm sorry.
我是来救你的 不是来跟你一起送命的
My plan was to get you out of here, not end up frozen beside you.
我辜负了你 也辜负了我的家人
I failed you. I failed my family.
如果没有英雄的出生入死
All the planning in the world doesn't amount to anything
任何计划都只是废纸一张
without a hero to make it happen.
我尽力了 弟弟
I tried, brother!
对不起
I'm sorry!
斯考奇
Scorch...
那是盖瑞的老婆？他怎么钓到手的
So that's Gary's wife? How'd he make that happen?
明白 他只会整天…
I know. Isn't he all like...
基普 我让你快逃的 你不该回来
Oh, Kip, I told you to run. You shouldn't have come back.
我不能丢下你 妈妈
I couldn't leave you, Mom.
小小探险者不会弃任何人于不顾
A Junior Adventurer never leaves a man behind.
基普 这不是玩游戏
Kipper, this isn't a game.
我知道 我已经不是小孩子了
I know. I'm not a little kid anymore.
所以我才会回来救你
That's why I came to rescue you.
你非常勇敢 但现在我们都被困在这了
And you're very brave, but now we're both stuck in here.
那是因为我还没有开始救你呢
That's because I'm not done rescuing you.
爆炸胶带 你是故意让他们抓你的
Blast tape? You let them catch you.
妈妈 你要保持安静
Mom, I'm gonna need you to be quiet.
基普 当心
Kip, be careful.
我们竟然沦落到看守柔弱妇孺
I can't believe we're guarding a lady and a kid.
- 太丢人了  - 这是托儿所吗
- It's embarrassing.  - Is this a daycare?
不关我的事哟
Here goes nothing.
把门打开 把门打开 快点
Open the door! Open the door! Hurry up!
基普 小心
Kip, look out!
你们已被放倒
Consider yourselves scorched!
快点 我们时间不多了
Come on, we don't have much time.
我去阻止那艘飞船
I've gotta stop that ship.
你去指挥中心藏起来 把门锁上
You go hide in Mission Control and lock that door behind you.
收到
Copy that!
这种恶棍行为不是你的风格
This whole villain thing, it's not you.
压力太大会加速衰老 如果我能…
You know? And the stress is aging you, if I might be...
闭嘴 你没有静音按钮吗
Shut up. Don't you have a mute button?
锁上了
It's locked.
我们政府认为小行星是地球最大的威胁
Our government thinks asteroids are Earth's biggest threat.
但我们更清楚 地球最大的威胁是？
But some of us know better. The biggest threat to planet Earth?
全球变暖
Global warming.
外星人
Aliens.
我们要先发制人 摧毁他们的星球
We will wipe out their planets before they come for us.
第一个目标是 巴卜星球
Our first target? Planet Baab!
是盖瑞的星球
That's Gary's planet!
正在锁定巴卜星球 成功锁定
Targeting planet Baab. Target acquired.
不好意思 长官 很抱歉打断你
Excuse me, sir? Sorry to interrupt.
只是想知道你大概什么时候送我们回家
Just wondering approximately what time you'll be sending us home.
他真的这么傻吗
Is he really this stupid?
你能去的地方只有冷冻仓
The only place you're going is the freezer.
这下你不会再乱发脾气了吧
Oh! I trust there'll be no more outbursts?
不
No!
危险 系统故障
Danger. System malfunction.
为什么运行不了
Why isn't it working?
[我们为和平而来]
盖瑞
Gary?
不 这是个圈套 关掉 关掉
No! It's a trap! Shut it down! Shut it down!
不
No!
系统超负荷
System overload.
快撤离 快撤离
Evacuate! Evacuate!
严重警告 快出去 大家快出去
Seriously. Get out of here. Everybody, out!
快跑 快离开
Scram. Gotta go. Uh-oh.
项圈掉了 我们自由了
They're off! We're free! Whoo!
你们会付出代价的 把他们都冻住
You're all gonna pay for this! Freeze the aliens!
独眼妹 起来 该发飙了 姑娘
Io, get up! It's time to get mad, girl.
制度怎么办
What about the program?
别管什么制度了
Forget the program!
能量大爆发
Tasers to full power!
接我一招
Yeah! Take that!
这就是招惹医生的下场
That's what you get when you mess with the Doc!
伙计们 我们得快点离开这里
Uh, guys? We might wanna get out of here!
斯考奇
Scorch!
斯考奇 醒醒
Scorch, hey! Come on!
- 斯考奇  - 盖瑞
- Scorch!  - Gary?
见到你真好
Oh, it's good to see you.
你还好吗
Are you OK?
当然了 没人能阻止斯考奇・超新星
Of course I am. Nothing can stop Scorch Supernova.
我的腿好像出了点问题
Ow! I'm having a bit of a leg situation over here.
你的腿还没有完全融化
You're still thawing out.
盖瑞 我太重了 你快逃吧
Gary, I'm too heavy. Go! Save yourself.
斯考奇 不行
Scorch, I couldn't.
我开玩笑的 快点 加把劲
I'm not serious! Come on, put some back into it!
带我出去
Get me outta here!
我自由了
I'm free!
蛇鲨怪
A Snarkbeast.
别担心 他们看着可怕 但完全无害
Don't worry. They look mean, but they're completely harmless.
我自由了
I'm free!
又不自由了
I'm not free.
我刚刚在想另外一种生物
Uh... Maybe I'm thinking of something else.
- 天啊  - 美味
- Oh, dear.  - Yummy!
- 不  - 我不会让你得逞的
- Oh, no!  - I don't think so.
滚开 我好饿
Got outta that place! I'm starving here!
放开我
Let me go!
独眼妹
Io!
快走 你救了我们 我们不能丢下你
Come on, now, you saved us. We couldn't leave you behind.
我们外星人很团结的
Us aliens gotta stick together.
你好 会说话的老鼠
Whoa! Hello, talking rat.
你非要这么鄙视我吗
Why you gotta disrespect me like that?
盖瑞 我爱死你的小脑袋了
Gary, I could kiss your brain!
破坏终极蓝核稳定性这招真妙
Destabilizing the Blubonium was brilliant.
他所有本事都是我教的
I taught him everything he knows.
他还没解冻 抬着他
He's still frozen. Grab a leg.
- 我全身都是粘液  - 我抬不动
- I'm covered in slime.  - I can't do this!
快点
Come on!
他们朝电梯去了
They're heading for the elevator.
- 立即上锁  - 随他们去
- Locking it down.  - Leave them.
这样他们就成了瓮中之鳖
They're sitting ducks in there.
阿尔法小队 他们朝你们那去了
Alpha Team, they're headed your way.
收到 长官 将冷冻枪调制最大功率
Copy that, sir. All right, boys, set your freezers to ice cold!
快点 快点
Move! Move! Move!
盖瑞 我们到楼顶之后应该怎么做
So, Gary, what's the plan when we reach the top?
给我点时间 我想想
Uh, just give me a second, let me think.
你最好快点想
You'd better think fast.
准备就绪
Here we go.
外星人 出来玩吧
Aliens, come out to play.
- 他们去哪儿了  - 我不知道
- Where'd they go?  - I don't know.
- 我没看见他们  - 他们不在这里
- I don't see 'em!  - They're not there!
他们跑掉了
They're gone. Huh?
现在
Now!
冻住他们
Freeze 'em!
- 抓住他们  - 开火
- Get 'em!  - Fire!
- 找到他 找到他  - 我来了
- Find him! Find him!  - I'm out!
你们居然能说服我干这个
I can't believe you talked me into this!
- 快开枪  - 不要冻…
- Shoot him!  - Don't freeze up out...
盖瑞 快看 我的手解冻了
Hey, Gary, check it out! The freezing wore off!
不是吧
Aw, come on!
看见了吗 老子是救世主
Whoo! Did you see that? I am the man!
- 我的嘴  - 快点 我们走
- My lips!  - Come on, come on, let's go!
我的嘴冻住了
Ouch! My lips got stuck!
只是一个简单的二进制电路
It's a simple binary lock circuit.
只要把集成电路的主开关接上
I'll just reconnect the main IC control switch...
我没教过你吗
Haven't I taught you anything?
搞定
Got it.
- 太棒了  - 自由了
- Yes!  - Freedom!
干得漂亮 老哥
Nice work, brother.
斯考奇 飞船在哪儿
Scorch, where's the ship?
跟我来 在这边
Follow me! It's this way!
事实上 在这边
Actually, it's this way.
我明白 当恶棍会很孤独
I get it. Being the villain can be lonely,
但在错误的地方是无法找到真爱的
but you're looking for love in all the wrong places.
他在利用你 一一三区的赞恩不好吗
He's using you. What's wrong with Zane in Sector 113?
- 小伙子很可爱…  - 闭嘴吧
- He's a lovely chap. Just...  - Shut up already!
连线沙克
Get me Shanker.
你要干什么 我现在很忙
What do you want? I'm kinda busy right now.
发生了什么 你的头发怎么回事
What's going on? What happened to your hair?
你送来的那两个蓝色蠢货把一切都毁了
Those blue idiots you sent ruined everything.
- 什么都没毁啊  - 这都是你的错
- Nothing's ruined.  - This is all your fault.
如果你不把东西送来 我们就分手
If you screw up this delivery, we 're through!
不 我会补偿你的 求你了
No! I'll make it up to you, please!
让飞船掉头吧
Turn this ship around.
琪拉 你在这里做什么
Huh? Kira? What are you doing here?
我们回家去
Let's go home.
看到我这幅样子你开心了吧
I bet it makes you happy seeing me like this.
不 怎么会呢
No, of course not.
我怎么会这么蠢
How could I have been so stupid?
他利用了我
He used me.
亡羊补牢为时未晚
It's never too late to do the right thing.
你跟盖瑞一样
You're just like Gary.
太天真 太幼稚了
So innocent. So naive.
拜托 莉娜 救我
Please! Lena, help me!
非要搞得两败俱伤吗
It doesn't have to be like this!
你以为你能阻止我 是吧
You thought you could stop me, didn't you?
家庭主妇妄想拯救宇宙
Little Miss Housewife saves the day!
你背叛了人民 背叛了你的星球
You've betrayed your people! You've betrayed your planet,
你穿这身制服丑的要死
and you're not fit to wear this uniform!
你以为女人有了孩子就威风不再了吗
What? You think just 'cause a chick has kids she can't dish it out?
电脑 重设航线返回巴卜星球
Computer, reset course to planet Baab.
快点 飞船就在下面
Hurry up! The ship's down there!
[拖车营地]
墨西哥卷饼吃多了
Whoo! I gotta lay off the burritos.
我把飞船伪装成他们飞船的样子
I cloaked it as one of their spaceships.
来吧
Come on!
- 对不住  - 伙计 能先敲门吗
- Sorry!  - Dude, don't you knock?
锤哥 快出来 太不可思议了
Hammer, get out here! You're never gonna believe this!
帅呆了
Awesome.
我走我走 这两艘不是 还剩一百艘要查
I'm going! I'm going! Nope! Two down, a hundred to go.
斯考奇 到底是哪艘啊
Scorch, which one is it?
蓝哥们 你还好吗
Blue buddy, what's up?
我弟弟伪装了我们的飞船然后找不到了
My brother cloaked our ship and lost it.
- 关门 我换衣服呢  - 不是
- Close the door! I'm changing!  - Nope! Ha!
包在我身上
No problem.
- 来个假警报？ - 对头
- False alarm?  - Yeah.
龙卷风来啦
Tornado!
- 龙卷风？ - 别挡道
- Tornado?  - Out of my way!
- 找掩护  - 我的老天
- Take cover!  - Oh, my God!
我的冰柜
My cooler!
快来 赶快
Come on, quick!
在那里
Aha! There it is!
好棒
Yes!
宝贝 我回来了
Hi, honey! I'm home!
- 搭便车喽  - 来了来了
- Sweet ride!  - There it is!
等等 你们不来绑架我们吗
Wait! Aren't you going to abduct us?
这个 其实我们不干那个
Uh, we don't really do that.
- 他们为和平而来  - 帅呆了
- They come in peace.  - Awesome.
飞吧 蓝哥们 飞吧
Fly, blue buddy! Fly!
- 我们要回家了  - 真棒
- Haha, we're going home!  - Yes!
盖瑞 棒极了
Gary, I love it!
打倒大反派 驾驶小飞船
Trashing bad guys, flying spaceships,
打虎还得靠亲兄弟啊
we might be related after all.
真奇怪 我觉得我会怀念这里的
You know, in some strange way, I'm gonna miss this place.
- 我恨死这里了  - 有追兵
- I hate this planet!  - We got company!
坐稳了
Hang on.
飞得真棒 盖瑞 没想到你还有这一手
Sweet flying, Gary! I didn't think you had it in you.
大家别惊慌 除了我以外
Nobody panic! I mean nobody else!
我来替大家惊慌
I'll panic for all of us.
我讨厌坐飞机
I don't fly well.
我想吐的时候 就用鼻子深呼吸
When I feel queasy, I try breathing deeply through my nose.
不要击落他们 沙克想要活口
Careful with your warning shots. Shanker wants 'em alive.
有导弹
Incoming!
- 我们被击中了  - 不要啊
- Oh, we're hit!  - Oh... no!
- 怎么回事  - 电脑被烧毁了
- What's going on?  - The computer's fried!
- 操纵杆失灵了  - 不要啊
- Our steering's gone.  - Oh, no!
电影里有这种情节 结局惨不忍睹
Oh, no! I've seen this in a movie! It does not end well!
求救 这里是超新星九号 我们即将坠落
Mayday! This is Supernova-9! We're going down!
求救 重复 我们即将坠落
Mayday! I repeat, we're going down!
我们失去动力了
We're a dead stick!
这里是超新星九号
This is the Supernova-9!
- 什么  - 我们即将坠落
- What?  - We are going down!
- 爸爸  - 基普
- Dad?  - Kipper!
- 是我 爸爸  - 你妈妈呢
- Yeah, it's me, Dad!  - Where's Mom?
找个大人来 我们有麻烦了
Put a grown-up on, bud, we're in trouble.
这里只有我一个人 爸爸
I'm the only one here, Dad.
基普 情况紧急 我们即将坠落
Kipper, this is serious. We're going down.
不 不会的
No, you're not.
基普 你要干吗
Kip, what are you doing?
超新星九号 转入远程协助模式
Supernova-9, you are go for remote assistance.
好 基普 这跟玩遥控飞船模型一样
OK, Kip, this is just like flying your remote control ship.
什么 这跟玩模型一点都不像
What? This is nothing like his remote control ship!
稍微往左一点
Just a little to the left.
左过头了 左过头了
Too much left! Too much left!
驾驶员是个菜鸟 大家自求多福吧
We got a student driver? Every man for himself.
我们要撞崖了 快拉升
Ah! We're gonna hit that cliff! Pull up!
打掉他们的引擎 让他们迫降
Take out their engines. Let's force them to land.
- 他们开火了  - 我们完蛋了
- They're shooting!  - We're not gonna make it!
我能搞定 爸爸 相信我
I've got this, Dad. Trust me.
拉升 拉升
Pull up! Pull up!
- 三  - 拉升
- Three  - Pull up!
- 基普  - 二
- Kip?  - Wwo
快升空
Pull up!
一
one.
弹射 弹射
Get out! Get out!
- 好  - 我们成功了
- Yes!  - We made it!
回头见 王八蛋
See ya later, suckers!
指挥中心 飞行技术真了得
Mission Control, that's some good flying.
- 我说过我能搞定  - 做得好 基普
- I told you, Dad, I got this.  - Way to go, Kipper.
斯考奇叔叔
Uncle Scorch?
大家都在 全部获救
Everyone is onboard and accounted for.
- 伙计们 和我儿子打个招呼  - 你好
- Hey, guys say hi to my son.  - Hi!
- 你好 小伙子  - 很高兴见到你
- What's up, little man?  - Pleased to meet you.
爸爸 你后面有东西
Dad, there's something coming up behind you!
什么
What?
盖瑞 我们的帐还没算完呢
Gary, I'm not finished with you!
是沙克
It's Shanker!
他穿了我的特工制服
He's got my mission suit.
我稍微改造了一下 喜欢吗
I made some modifications. You like them?
怎么回事 你们怎么不动了
What's going on? Why aren't you moving?
我们被困在牵引光波里 你得把我们弄出去
We're caught in a tractor beam. You've gotta get us out of it!
没反应 飞船会烧毁的
It's not working. We're burning up!
我们必须把光波击断
We gotta knock off that tractor beam.
没错 盖瑞 怎么击断
Nice one, Gary. How do we do that?
从光源处击断
We take it out at the source.
你是说下去那里
You mean go down there?
理智点 盖瑞 你这是让我去送死
Be logical, Gary. You're asking me to jump with no chance of survival.
我没让你做任何事情
I'm not asking you to do anything.
盖瑞
Gary!
- 他成功了  - 加油 盖瑞
- He made it!  - Come on, Gary!
放开我兄弟
Get your hands off my brother!
- 斯考奇 你来干什么  - 我们是搭档
- Scorch, what are you doing?  - We're a team, brother!
- 不记得了吗  - 救命
- Don't you remember?  - Aah! Help!
伙计 我们正在煽情呢
Hey, pal, we're having a moment here.
把你的脸从我手上拿开
Get your face out of my hand!
别揪我头发
Let go of my hair!
快点
Hurry up!
这就是死期了
I guess this is it.
我们是对好搭档
We were a good team!
知道吗 我一直很钦佩你
You know, I always looked up to you.
- 你钦佩我？ - 我认真的
- You looked up to me?  - I'm serious.
有个好老婆 好儿子
Great wife, great kid.
我总想着有一天也能拥有这些
I always thought I could do that one day.
你一定会是个好爸爸
You would've been a great dad.
- 盖瑞  - 怎么了 老弟
- Hey, uh, Gary?  - Yeah, brother?
抱歉 我开除了你
I'm sorry for firing you.
明明是我辞职了
Actually, I quit.
怎么…
Huh? What the...?
- 盖瑞  - 怎么
- Gary!  - What...?
是你们 谢谢
You! Thank you.
不用谢
Don't mention it.
- 你们会说话？ - 当然
- You can talk?  - Of course.
- 偶尔说一说  - 时不时来几句
- Occasionally.  - From time to time.
为什么救我们 你们不是疯将军的人吗
Why did you save us? I thought you worked for General Crazy.
开始 我们很抱歉压扁了他老爸
At first, we felt bad for squishing his dad.
后来发现他是个神经病自大狂
Turns out he was a psychopathic megalomaniac
每天都想着怎么消灭宇宙间所有智能生命
bent on destroying every known form of intelligent life in the universe.
人心隔肚皮
Who knew?
你们要怎么处置他
What are you gonna do with him?
- 无可奉告  - 你们知道了会做恶梦的
- Can't say.  - It'll give you nightmares.
你会付出代价的
You're gonna pay for this.
我告诉过你 我们为和平而来
I thought I told you, we come in peace!
好疼
Ouch! Oh, wow.
- 第一次出拳吧  - 没错
- First punch-out?  - Yeah.
- 感觉不错吧  - 是啊 感觉好极了
- Feels good, doesn't it?  - Oh, yeah. Yeah, feels great.
刚才太帅了 我本想跟着跳的
That was amazing! I would've jumped, too,
但貌似你俩已经完全镇住场面了
but it looked like you guys had everything under control.
这小不点太好玩了
This little guy's great.
- 能留着养吗  - 放我下来
- Can we keep him?  - Put me down!
我们回家吧
Let's go home.
好吧
All right!
回家的感觉真好
Ah, it's good to be home.
指挥中心 请求着陆
Mission Control, bring us in.
看你的六点钟方向 超新星九号
Check your six, Supernova-9.
- 你好 亲爱的  - 琪拉 你怎么来了
- Hiya, honey!  - Kira? How did you...?
那是我老婆
That's my wife!
盖瑞 你怎么钓到那样的美女的
Oh, Gary, how'd you hook that up?
我一直觉得你是个…
I always thought you were a little...
这是什么意思 每个人都这么说
What does that mean? Everybody always says that.
问倒我了
Beats me.
和斯考奇一起 意外早已是家常便饭
I've come to expect the unexpected working with Scorch,
但我完全没有料到
but I don't think anything could have prepared me
竟然会跟家人一起拯救我们的星球
for working with my family to save our planet.
生命果然充满了不可预料
I guess life's pretty unpredictable after all.
斯考奇 你是最棒的
Yay, Scorch, you're the best!
你太棒了
You're so awesome!
真棒 斯考奇
Yay, Scorch!
我爱你 巴卜星球
I love you, planet Baab!
- 斯考奇  - 好棒
- Yeah, Scorch!  - Yes!
- 好厉害 斯考奇  - 你救了我们
- Way to go, Scorch!  - You saved us!
别再逞英雄了 行吗
No more hero stuff for a while, OK?
开什么玩笑 我连家门也不想出了
Are you kidding? I'm never leaving the house again.
- 爸爸  - 我们爱你 伙计
- Dad!  - We love you, buddy!
基普
Kipper!
基普 你做的太好了
Kipper, that was amazing.
真为你自豪 伙计
We're so proud of you, bud.
你表现的和你的叔叔一样耀眼
You were awesome out there, just like your uncle.
你一定会成为伟大的航天员的
You are gonna be a great astronaut one day.
可能和我并驾齐驱哦
Maybe even as good as me.
谢了 斯考奇叔叔
Thanks, Uncle Scorch.
但我更想当一个指挥人员
But I'm more of a mission controller.
像我爸一样
Like my dad.
嘉比・泡泡娃 巴卜星电视台记者 借过
Gabby Babblebrock, BNN, coming through!
见到你真好
Oh, it's good to see you!
嘉比・泡泡娃 巴卜星电视台
Gabby Babblebrock, BNN.
分享一下全宇宙第一英雄的心情故事吧
Tell us what it's like to be the greatest hero in the universe.
这你可得问他本人了
You're gonna have to ask him yourself.
给我的老弟盖瑞・超新星来点掌声
Give it up for my little brother, Gary Supernova!
其实我比他大
Hey, I'm older than him.
- 盖瑞 盖瑞  - 我们还是好搭档吗
- Gary! Gary!  - So Gary, we still a team?
总得有人帮你 老弟
Somebody's gotta watch your back. Little brother.
这就是我老弟 斯考奇 他又有麻烦了
That's my brother, Scorch. He's in trouble, again.
七十二小时之后
Seventy-two hours later,
他经历了人生中最严峻的考验
he was on the most terrifying mission of his life.
斯考奇 能听到吗
Scorch, do you copy?
能 兄弟 我腿都吓软了
Yeah, brother. I'm scared to move.
记住你的训练 你能行的
Remember your training. You can do this.
- 我做不了 盖瑞  - 别这么说
- I'm not gonna make it, Gary.  - Don't say that.
我会全程步步紧跟你的
I'll be by your side every step of the way.
我的搭档吗
My wingman?
是你的伴郎
Your best man.
斯考奇・超新星 你愿意
And do you, Scorch Supernova,
接受嘉比・泡泡娃成为你合法的妻子吗
take Gabby Babblebrock to be your lawfully wedded wife,
- 永不分离  - 独眼妹 你在哭吗
- to have and to hold...  - Oh, Io, are you crying?
我只是眼里进了沙子
No, I just got something in my eye.
伙计们 让我们永不分离
Let's never break up, guys.
嘉比・泡泡娃 你愿意接受斯考奇・超新星
And do you, Gabby Babblebrock, take Scorch Supernova
- 为你的合法丈夫吗  - 我愿意
- to be your lawfully wedded husband?  - I do.
那么现在 凭借
And so, by the power vested in me
银河系无线电脱口秀心理医生协会
by the Intergalactic Association of Radio Talk Show Therapists,
赐予我的权力 我宣布你们结为夫妇
I now pronounce you husband and wife.
你可以亲吻新娘了
You may kiss the bride.
派对开始吧
Let's party!
- 斯考奇 干得不错啊  - 多谢光临
- Hey, Scorch, way to go, man!  - Hey, thanks for coming.
不是吧 你竟然没事
No! You're OK!
不敢相信你活过来了
I can't believe you made it!
真高兴见到你
Nice to meet you.
又来了
Here we go again.
大家一起摇摆起来吧
Yeah! That's it, that's it!
没错
Oh! Oh, yeah!
来吧 盖瑞
Come on, Gary.
好吧 虽然有点丢人
Well, this is humiliating.
你大可不必穿越百万光年
You know, you don't have to travel millions of light-years
去打败银河系终极大坏蛋
and defeat a deadly intergalactic enemy
因为你最后总会发现
to find out that the greatest
和你的兄弟 和你的家人
story of all is right here on your home planet,
一起度过的故乡生活才是最精彩的故事
with your brother, and your own family.
我爱你们
Love you guys!